本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
■
圣  城  风  云
『第一季  第六集』
翻译  Jasmine雪
翻译  LyraL
翻译  ala365
翻译  苏小黛
翻译  小易
时间轴  veryink
校对  苏小黛
后期  渔夫
特效  WiLL
总监制  苏小黛
当宙斯问他女儿阿尔特弥斯
When Zeus asked his daughter, Artemis,
阿尔特弥斯  希腊神话中的月亮兼狩猎女神
想要什么作为三岁生日的礼物时
what she would like for her third birthday,
她向他要了六个愿望
she requested that he grant her 6 wishes.
第一个愿望是
The first wish was
可以过自己想过的生活
that she be allowed to live her life
不用受爱情或婚姻的困扰
without the distraction of love or marriage.
第二个愿望是成为生命的使者
The second wish was to be the bringer of life...
桂妮维尔  有位信使要见你
Guinevere! There's a messenger here to see you.
他说很紧急
He says it's urgent.
进来吧  布里奇特
Coming, Bridget.
-来吧  -起
- Come on! - Up!
继续
Come again!
-卡米洛特万岁  -加油  伙计们
- Camelot! - Come on lads,
使出吃奶的劲  这是国王的命令
put your backsides into it, would you! King's orders.
用力推
Push!
妈的  这领土面积还真大
Bloody hell, it's a big territory.
把它插牢了
Stick it well in, now.
你真觉得这会有意义吗
You really think these will make a difference?
国王认为有意义
The King does.
看着不错  但总有一天
Well, they look good. Until they're pulled
会被人拔掉当作柴火用
out of the ground and used for firewood.
这些旗帜会将我们的信息传得更远
These banners push our message further.
会向人们昭示这是亚瑟王的土地
They tell people they're in King Arthur's land...
是受到保护的
That they're protected.
都上马吧  我们还有活要干
On your horses, all of you. We've work to do.
你说什么呢
What do you mean?
我们正在干活啊
We're doing the work.
还有更重要的任务  我们要回你的老家
We've a higher priority. We're going to your old home.
为什么
Why?
为了你父亲多年积攒下的书籍
For the library your father put together.
用不着所有人都去吧  巫师
That doesn't need all of us, Sorcerer.
对于我们来说  书如黄金般珍贵
Books are as valuable to us as gold.
-他明白的  -我们得尽快
- Oh, he knows that. - We should have done this sooner.
我们有了军械库  现在需要一个藏书馆
We have an armoury, we need a library.
所以  走吧
So, let's go.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
没事
Yes.
我只是从未想过还会回去
I just never thought I'd be going back there.
我们进度太慢了
We're moving too slowly.
这些楼层需要修缮确保安全
The floors need to be made safe.
清理出更多可居住的房间
More rooms cleared for living space.
把花花草草还有太茂盛的树木都拔掉
Strip out the plants and overgrowth.
我们需要
Oh, and we'll need, uh,
椽子来修复大厅的屋顶
rafters to repair the roof in the Great Hall.
殿下  亚瑟
Your Highness. Arthur.
-什么事 -桂妮维尔走了
- What? - Guinevere's gone!
走了是什么意思
What do you mean gone?
她刚才独自一人骑马出去了
She rode out just now by herself.
抱歉  除了您  我不知道还能找谁了
I'm sorry, I didn't know who else to talk to.
她去哪儿了
Where did she go?
您最好和信使谈谈
You should talk to the messenger.
她父亲格兰斯病重
Her father, Leodegrance, he's sick.
将不久于人世
He has only a few days to live.
他派我来召她回去
He sent me from the Fenlands
我是从东边的沼泽地过来的
in the east to summon her.
考虑到路途遥远  他可能已经死了
But with the length of the journey, he may be dead already.
能派些人跟着她吗
Can we send some men out after her?
不行  人基本都被派出去标定国界了
No, most are already out marking the territories.
-她一个人不安全  -我去跟着她
- She's not safe out there on her own! - I'll go.
让开  给国王让路
Make way! Make way for the King!
他们等了多久了
How long have they been waiting?
从日出起他们就陆续而至
They started coming at sunrise.
他们都为了同样目的而来...
They all want the same thing...
希望国王的姐姐能聆听他们的烦恼
to have the ear of the King's sister.
我早说过他们会来的
I told you they'd come.
你必须以此来扩大影响力
Your influence can only grow from this.
免礼
Don't kneel.
告诉我  你们为何而来
Tell me why you're here.
是为了我儿子
It's about my boy.
我和孩子他父亲分开已经七年了
Me and his father, we haven't been together for 7 years...
他和另一个女人跑了
He went off with another woman.
现在他想让我儿子去他农场做苦力
Now he wants the boy to help with the labour on his farm.
但他父亲没有抚养他  是我抚养他的
But his father didn't raise him, I did.
他该和我呆在一起
He should stay with me.
你来找我是希望我帮你解决纠纷吗
And you came to me so I would settle your feud?
我带了份礼物给您  一些我家自产的奶
I bought you a gift,some milk from my herd.
你就是孩子的父亲
You're the father.
你凭什么要这个孩子
Why should you have him?
她一直不让我见他
She's always kept him from me.
我需要人帮我干活
I need help with the work.
找他是理所当然  而且他是我唯一的家人
He's old enough to be called on. And he's the only family I have.
你们是否发誓遵从我的决定
Do you both swear to abide by my decision?
-我发誓  -我遵从
- Yes. - I do.
我想向你们买下这孩子
Then I'll buy the child from you.
什么
What?!
我会出个好价钱的
For a good price.
他可以在这里做仆人
He can live here as a servant.
以五头山羊作为交换
Five goats in exchange for him.
我不是为此而来的
That's not why I came!
五头山羊外加两头绵羊
Five goats and 2 sheep.
不行
No.
十头山羊外加五头绵羊  他还小
Ten goats and 5 sheep. He's young,
但他会长大变强壮  他会好好给你干活的
but he'll grow strong. You'll get good work from him.
七头山羊外加三头绵羊
Seven goats, 3 sheep.
你不能这么做
You can't do this!
-九头山羊...  -八头
- Nine goats... - Eight.
外加三头绵羊  这孩子是你的了
And 3 sheep. The boy's yours for that.
-直接付款  -不行
- Immediate payment. - No!
很好
Good!
这孩子和母亲呆一起
The child stays with his mother!
什么
What?
我们不是刚达成协议了吗
We just made a deal!
你为了几只羊就肯出卖自己的儿子
You bartered your son for nothing.
你不配做一名父亲  滚
You're not worthy to be called a father. Get out.
快走  赶紧滚
Go on! Out with you!
谢谢
Thank you.
你有个称职的母亲
You have a good mother.
要好好对她
Treasure her.
下一个
Next!
袭击他们的人有可能还在这里
Whoever attacked them could still be here.
救救我
Help.
没事了
It's all right.
-我的妻子...  -别动
- My wife... - Don't move.
他们杀了她吗
Did they spare her?
不管是什么人  他们已经走了
Whoever they were, they've moved on.
我要死了吗
Am I dying?
是的  不管你的信仰是什么
Yes. Whatever you believe in,
现在都是时候安息了
now's the time to make your peace.
-你就不能救救他吗  -你能吗
- Can't you help him? - Can't you?
你有魔法啊  不是吗
You have powers, don't you?
你到底以为我能做什么啊
What exactly do you think I'm capable of?
这个人需要你的帮助
A man needs your help here.
我们都各有气数
We each have our time.
而他气数已尽
His is done.
你这是什么意思
What are you saying?
救救我
Help me.
-求你  -你受伤太重
- Please. - Your wounds are too great.
我们会为你的灵魂祈祷的
We'll pray for your soul.
要我帮忙吗
Can I help?
好的
Yes.
放松
Easy.
我去挖坑安葬他
I'll dig a grave.
-桂妮维尔  -你怎么来了
- Guinevere. - What're you doing here?
你自己骑马跑了
You rode off on your own.
我父亲要死了
My father's dying.
我听说了  我很遗憾
I heard. I'm sorry.
停下
Stop.
自我大婚后  他就跟他妹妹住在东边
He's been living with his sister, out east, since the wedding.
这样不安全
It's not safe!
要是换了你会怎么做
What would you do if you were me?
-谢谢  -你往哪去
- Thank you. - Where you heading?
-东边  -别从林子里走
- Out east. - Not through the forest.
昨晚又有一起袭击
There was another attack last night.
你妻子不该去那种地方
That's no place for your wife.
我不是他妻子
I'm not his wife.
我不该多管闲事
None of my business.
-这种情况有多久了  -一直都有
- How long has it been like that? - Oh, since always.
经常有受伤的人从这里经过
We get people through here, they're wounded,
他们非常害怕
and they're scared.
这些人只是想苟且谋生罢了
They're just trying to make a living.
人们都说有了...
People said it would be...
有了新国王一切会有所不同
...it would be different with the new King.
但是没有  他没为我们做什么
But no. He's done nothing for us.
也许他已经尽力了
Maybe he's doing his best.
毕竟任务不轻啊
It's a big task.
但他若有心
But he wanted it.
就该做得更好一些
You'd think he'd be better at it.
-我陪你去  -你这样做比我更危险
- I'll accompany you. - You're in more danger than I am.
国王独自出行
The King travelling alone?
没带旗  没带印  在卡米洛特城外
No banners, no seals. Outside of Camelot,
显然没几个人能认出我来
hardly anyone knows what I look like, apparently.
如果你因为我而受伤了
If you get hurt because of me...
我们走海边
We'll take the coast,
不走林子
not the forest.
里昂提斯救过我的命
Leontes saved my life.
我起码该保护我护卫的妻子
The least I can do is guard my champion's wife.
我会送你去见你父亲
I'll take you to your father.
为了里昂提斯
For Leontes.
-为了你们两个人  -别无他意
- For both of you. - No other reason?
过去的已经过去了
The past is done with.
谢谢
Thank you.
她在休息
She's resting.
-你们去哪儿  -她在哪
- Where are you going? - Where is she?
国王的姐姐  我要马上见到她
The King's sister. I need to see her immediately.
她按顺序接见人  而且她今天见的人
She sees people in order. And she has more than enough
已经够多的了
to see today.
大门明天会再次敞开的
The gates will be open again tomorrow.
不行  她得见我们
No. She needs to see us.
马上
Now.
我们出发以来  你几乎没说过话
You've hardly said anything since we set off.
是因为那个女人说的话吗
Is it what that woman said?
我该怎么做  我们标记了北边的领地
How do I make it work? We stake our territory to the North,
东边的人民就受扰  我解决了东边峡谷的事端
people to the East are vulnerable. I tackle the valleys
南边又有人入侵
in the East, we face incursion from the South.
每一次我失败  或是有所疏漏
Every time I fail, or make an omission,
或是有所偏颇  我就要为
or prioritize, I'm responsible
另一个地方的死亡负责
for a death somewhere else.
现在人人都指望着我了
Everyone looks to me now.
我看到你怎样处理凯特琳父亲的听证会了
I saw how you handled the hearing with Katelyn's father.
你听他们陈述  然后提出质疑
You listened and you questioned.
即使这听证会本来就是你召开的
Even the fact you convened it in the first place.
你理解人民疾苦  你在乎他们
You understand the people, and you care.
你做得很好
Well done.
家庭纠纷  领土纷争
Family disagreements, territorial wrangling...
你都处理得非常好
You handled them all superbly.
等时候到了
And when the time comes,
他们都会对你忠心不二的
all of them shall owe you loyalty.
但现在你该用用你的新魔法了
But now you must apply yourself to your new powers.
你把这魔法请来的
You asked for them,
为什么却不愿使用呢
and yet you shy away from using them. Why?
你很清楚
You know why.
因为我无法忍受穿着她的皮囊
Because I can't bear to be in her skin.
理由不够好
Not good enough.
这是赐予你的天赋
You've been given a gift.
好好利用
Use it.
抱歉打扰您  有个女人
I'm sorry to disturb you. There's a woman
她在大厅里  坚持要马上见您
in the hall insisting on speaking to you immediately.
让她像其他人一样排队等候
Tell her to wait her turn like everyone else.
我说了  只是
I did. It's just...
她说您身处极度危险之中
...she says you're in terrible danger.
你在想你的父亲吗
Are you thinking about your father?
我昨晚梦到他了  仿佛是他在召唤我
Last night I dreamt of him as if he was calling me.
我以前从没梦到过他
I never dreamt of him before.
我们会赶到的
We'll get to him.
如果你能拥有原来的生活  你会接受吗
If you could have your old life back, would you take it?
如果我说会  那意味着我的父母将还在人世
If I said yes, it would mean my parents would be alive.
我将回到过去  对现在的一切一无所知
But I'd be back there and know none of this,
但是
and the thing is,
我爱这种生活
I love it.
你的口气好像是以此为耻似的
You say that like you should be ashamed.
我是刚才才意识到这些的
I didn't realize it until just now.
是谁召唤我来
Who has summoned me?
我们得单独谈谈
We need to speak alone.
在我的子民面前  我没什么好遮掩的
I have nothing to hide from my people.
你没有
You may not,
但你身边的那个女人有
but the woman at your side does.
你们认识吗
Do you know each other?
我不确定
I can't tell.
-取下你的面纱  -你无权命令我
- Take off your veil. - You don't order me.
你告诉她了吗  她知道吗
Have you told her? Does she know?
我不知道你什么意思
I don't know what you mean.
国王的姐姐在庇护一个恶魔
The King's sister harbours a devil.
什么
What?
为何要遮住你的脸  我能一睹芳容吗
Why do you keep your face covered? May I see?
好吧  也许你看到我就会明白了
Yes. Maybe then you'll understand.
怎么回事
How did it happen?
我的女儿在房子里
My daughter was in the building.
她传了个信叫我过去
She'd sent a message for me to come.
我赶到那里  但为时已晚
I got there too late.
着火的时候我也在里面
I was inside when it started.
火焰犹如魔鬼般迅速蔓延...
The flames spread like the devil himself...
遍及大门  地面
Across the doorways, the floors.
接着我听到了她的惨叫
And then I heard her.
这发生在哪里
Where was this?
海对面的修道院
The nunnery across the sea.
我知道你曾在那里住过
I know you were there once.
所以你才会允许她待这里吗
Is that why you allowed her here?
是我主动来她身边的  她需要我
I came to be at her side. She needed me.
当然了
Of course.
你以为没人找得到你
You thought no one would find you.
但找你是我的使命
But I've made it my mission.
是你纵的火
You lit that fire.
修道院被烧
The nunnery burned
-你便是罪魁祸首  -不
- because of you. - No.
我逃出了火场
I pulled myself out,
看到了你
and I saw you,
你躲那里  而我女儿却在垂死哀嚎
hiding as my daughter died screaming.
这不可能
It can't be!
你想怎么样
What do you want?
惩戒
Retribution.
什么程度的惩戒
To what end?
为了我死去的女儿
For the daughter I lost.
你必须公正地审判
You must sit in judgment on
你一直窝藏的女人
the woman you've been harbouring.
她必须被处决
She must be executed.
游得怎么样
How was your swim?
海水冷吗
Was the water cold?
很冷  但我还是得游
Freezing. But I have to swim.
为什么
Why?
为了忘却自己
To forget myself.
为了有片刻脱离尘世
To lose the world for a moment.
尝尝国王的盛宴
The King's feast.
谢谢
Thank you.
你为什么不救他
Why didn't you save him?
我救不了将死之人
I can't stop people dying
或把他们复活
or bring them back from the dead
就跟你们一样
any more than you can.
那么你不是个巫师
So you're not a sorcerer.
那个词对我来说是种侮辱
The word's an insult.
你的魔法是学来的
Did you study magic,
还是与生俱来的
or were you born with it?
都不是
Neither.
那你是怎么会魔法的
So where does it come from?
思索...就会显现
Thought... made manifest.
那样说不通
That doesn't make any sense.
如果我说是上帝赐予的  你就满意了么
Would you be happier if I said it was a gift from God?
那样说我就明白了
It would be clearer to me.
听着  力量存在于火中
Listen, there are forces in the fire,
风中  水中
wind, water,
土中
the earth.
我能用意念重组这些元素...
I can shape these elements to my will...
在某种...微小的程度上
In some... small degree.
不  那是上帝在帮你
No, that's God working through you.
不可能  上帝并不存在
Unlikely, given there is no God.
梅林  我从尤瑟的临终之床
Merlin, I followed you
跟随你到卡米洛特
from Uther's deathbed to Camelot.
我是国王最忠诚的骑士
I'm the King's most loyal knight.
我对你别无所求  只求你尊重我的信仰
All that I ask is that you respect my faith.
就像你尊重我的信仰一样吗
Like you respect mine?
我不理解你的信仰
I don't understand it,
但我并没不尊重
but I don't disrespect it.
我没因你所做之事  而叫你魔鬼
You don't hear me call you a devil for what you do.
那你叫我什么呢
Then what would you call me? Hmm?
可能是天使吧
An angel perhaps?
我有过很多称呼  但从未被这样叫过
I've been called a lot of things, but never that.
真好
Perfect.
那你能召唤风暴卷走这一切吗
So you could summon a storm to blow all this away?
不  那太庞大了
No. Too big.
那代价会要了我的命
The cost would kill me.
什么样的代价
What sort of cost?
既有身体的  也有心理的
On the body. The soul.
它们缠绕在我周围
And those around me.
我会沉迷其中
It's an addiction.
每次清醒之后  我都会克制自己
One which I deny myself every waking hour.
怎么搞的  现在发生这种事
Not now. Of all the times, not now!
我能帮你什么
Is there anything I can get you?
在那些人面前
And in front of all those people!
想想他们会怎么说
Think of what they'll say.
想像一下这事会传播得多块...
Imagine how fast this is spreading...
摩根审判其他人
That Morgan judges others,
却留了个凶手在身边
but keeps a murderer close!
那里没多少人...
There were only a few people there...
那没什么区别  他们会散播流言
That makes no difference! They'll gossip!
他们就爱散播流言
They love to gossip.
我们所做一切不能付之一炬
What we are doing must not be undermined.
这太重要了
It's too important.
她怎么可以这样对我
How could she do this to me?
她怎么可以瞒着我
How could she not tell me?
你会怎么做
What will you do?
我别无选择
I don't have a choice.
我必须公开审理
I must have a public hearing.
公众必须知晓事实
The facts must be heard.
你觉得这事是真的吗
Do you think it's true?
我不需要你质疑我  薇薇安
I don't need you questioning me too, Vivian.
对不起  我没那意思
I'm sorry. I didn't mean anything by it.
为什么是现在
Why now?
就在人们开始信任我之时
When people were starting to believe in me.
西比尔请求见你
Sybil asked if she could see you.
这样她就可以再对我撒谎吗
So she can lie to me?
说服我吗
Talk me round? Ha!
告诉她我身体欠安
Tell her I'm indisposed.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
我能安排得神不知鬼不觉
I can arrange it so no one would know or see.
告诉她  我明天公审前见她
Tell her I'll see her tomorrow at the hearing.
我们将查明真相
And we shall uncover the truth.
如果是真的  你会怎么处理
If it's true, what will you do?
够了  薇薇安
That will be all, Vivian.
救救我  救救我
Help me! Help me!
救命啊  来人哪
Help, somebody!
你认为天上那些是什么
What do you think they are, up there?
可能是众神的眼睛在关注着我们
Maybe the eyes of the gods keeping watch.
或是一个神的很多眼睛
Or the many eyes of a single God.
目光遍及各地
Spread across every land,
关注着一切
seeing everything.
我不知道
I don't know.
我很抱歉发生的那些事
I'm sorry for everything that's happened.
很抱歉发生的一切
I'm sorry for it all.
没什么可道歉的
There's nothing to apologize for.
谢谢
Thank you.
拿那个
Take that.
亚瑟
Arthur,
有人
There's somebody here.
还有一个
And the other one.
过来  你  过来
Come here, you! Come here!
别杀我  求你了
No, please!
把东西放下
Put it down,
不然我把你的脸放火里烤
or I put your face in the fire.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
这里被抢劫过了
It's been plundered.
你真认为他们把书籍留下了
Your really think they left the books?
我希望这帮蛮夷之徒
I'm hoping a barbarian's thugs
不识这里的珍宝
didn't realize the treasures that lay here.
你准备好了吗
Are you ready?
真是恍如隔世
This feels another life away.
我先进去
I'll go in first.
我一直欺骗自己说  他日我走进这房间时
I've been kidding myself I could walk back in
我父母会还在这里
and my parents would still be here.
我明白
I know.
书籍不见了  梅林
The books are gone, Merlin.
不
No...
它们必须在这里
They have to be here!
它们不在
They're not.
这说不通
It doesn't make any sense.
也许被人拿走  或是当柴火烧了
Maybe someone took them, or used them as fuel for their fires.
过来受审
Come and be judged.
你已听到指控
You've heard the accusation.
对此有何回应
What do you say in response?
首先
First of all,
我是来请求原谅的
I come to ask forgiveness.
原谅  你杀了我女儿
Forgiveness? You killed my daughter!
让她说
Let her speak.
是你放火烧了修道院吗
Did you burn the nunnery?
是的
Yes.
告诉我们发生了什么
Tell us what happened.
世上有一些力量
There are forces in this world
若想牵制住它们
which must be satisfied
就必须先满足他们
if they are to be kept at bay.
有一项祭典
There was a ritual.
每年选一名女孩献祭
Every year, one girl was selected.
信奉上帝并不意味着我们要放弃旧方式
Embracing God did not mean we abandoned the old ways.
你对我女儿做了什么
What did you do to my daughter?
什么也没有  我发誓
Nothing. I swear.
-你在修道院向魔鬼献祭女孩  -不
- You offered girls to the devil in a nunnery! - No.
不是向魔鬼
Not the devil.
只有少数人明白祭祀的必要性
Only a few understood the necessity of the ritual.
多数人不理解
Many did not.
那天晚上  牧师们到来
That night, the priests came,
寻找祭祀的证据
looking for evidence of the ceremony.
所以我放了火
So I burned it.
但火势蔓延  我无法阻止
But the fire spread. I couldn't stop it.
我跳窗才逃出生天
I only survived by jumping from a window.
每天晚上
Every night...
我都听到她的尖叫
...I hear her screams.
看见她的脸
And see her face.
犹若恶魔  萦绕于心
It haunts me like a demon.
这就是你想说的一切吗
Is that everything you wish to say?
这改变不了什么
This changes nothing!
处决才是唯一正义的决定
An execution is the only just decision.
这关乎一个女人的生死
A woman's life is at stake.
我需要时间考虑
I shall take time to consider.
当我准备好后  你们会听到我的决定
When I'm ready, you shall hear my decision.
现在都退下吧
Now clear the hall.
那是他的盾牌
That's his shield.
他已经逝去了  是吗
He's already dead, isn't he?
无论如何  你都可以面对
Whatever you find here, you can face it.
你来了
You came!
-他肯定会高兴的  -莎拉姑姑
- He'll be so pleased.  - Aunt Sara.
他说过你会来的
He said you'd come.
-他深信不疑  -他怎样了
- He was so sure.  - How is he doing?
饱受痛楚
In a lot of pain.
他一直坚持着等你回来  快进去吧
He's holding on for you. Go on through.
你来了
You came.
是的
Yes.
我想你  爱丽丝
I missed you, Alice.
不  父亲
No, Father.
是我
It's me.
桂妮维尔
Guinevere.
我们还能为他做点什么吗
Is there anything else we can do for him?
只需陪着他
Just be with him.
当宙斯问他女儿阿耳特弥斯
When Zeus asked his daughter, Artemis,
想要什么作为三岁生日的礼物时
what she wanted for her third birthday,
她向他要了六个愿望
she requested that he grant her 6 wishes.
第一个愿望是
The first wish was that she be allowed
可以过自己想过的生活
to live her life...
不用受爱情或婚姻的困扰
...without the distraction of love and marriage.
我不明白...
Here's what I don't understand...
说来话长
Oh, this could take a while.
有意思
Very funny.
你带亚瑟来到卡米洛特
You bring Arthur to Camelot.
你四处招兵买马
You recruit warriors from throughout the realm.
告诉我们使出看家本领为新王效命
You tell all of us to use our skills to serve the new King.
可你自己却不拿出真本事
And yet you won't use yours for the same end.
这不一样
It's different.
为什么  你比我们优秀吗
Why? You're better than us?
因为我厌恶体内的这股力量
Because I loathe this power inside me.
因为它让我恐惧
Because it terrifies me.
因为你否认它
Because you deny it.
因为这力量控制着你
Because it controls you.
因为它把我推向黑暗
Because it pulls me to the dark.
那就阻止它
Then don't let it.
你觉得这与我们学习格斗
You think this is any different than any of us learning combat,
学习克制愤怒以提高技能有所不同吗
learning to suppress rage for greater skill?
我们都在奋斗抗争  都在学习控制
We all struggle, we all fight, and we all learn to control.
你天赋异禀  梅林
You have a raw power, Merlin.
不要否定  而要学习爱上这力量
But instead of denying it, learn to love it.
想象一下到那时你的能力
Imagine what you could be capable of then.
那时你能为卡米洛特带来的一切
What you could bring to Camelot.
以前为何不告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?
我羞愧难当
I was ashamed.
你来这是因为觉得自己会很安全
You came here because you thought you'd be safe.
不
No.
我是来帮你的
I came here to help you
治愈你的病痛
through your sickness.
看看现在的你
And look at you now.
离王位只有一步之遥
On the verge of the throne.
看你得到了什么  无比的力量
Look at what you've got. So much strength.
只差咫尺之遥
You're so close.
你不能让这个
You mustn't let this...
这个误会  将我们的心血毁了
...this misunderstanding push us off course.
作为国王的姐姐
As the King's sister,
我不能无视教条
I can't ignore what I've been told.
我明白
I understand.
别抛弃我
Don't abandon me.
摩根  求你了
Morgan, please!
晚安  西比尔
Good night, Sybil.
这是他的斗篷
This was his cloak.
他要我确保它归你所有
He said I was to make sure you had it.
谢谢
Thank you.
说点什么好吗
Would you say something?
谢谢你们赶来
Thank you all for being here.
这对他来说意义深重
I'm sure it meant a lot to him.
我很高兴他来这里跟你们同住
I'm so glad he came to be with you here,
你们陪伴他走到了最后
and that you could be near him at the end.
我们对死亡都有着各自的见解
We all have our own ideas of what death might be.
但我们都知道
For all we know,
死亡也许是最好的解脱
Death could be the greatest good that could happen to us.
西塞罗说过  逝去的生命
Cicero said, "The life of the dead
将在记忆中永垂
is placed in the memories of the living".
我们活着时感受到的爱
The love we feel in life
能让人们超脱肉体  永远活下去
keeps people alive beyond their time.
我的父母就无时不与我同在
There isn't a day my parents aren't with me.
他们活在我的记忆中  我的血肉里
In my memories, and in who I am.
但凡有爱之人
Anyone who has given love will always live on
必将被人所爱  永世铭记
in another's heart.
一切都在改变
All is change.
一切来去匆匆
All yields its place and goes.
坚持不懈  秉持信仰
To persevere, trusting in what hopes he has,
才是男人的勇气所在
is courage in a man.
只有懦夫才会绝望
Only the coward despairs.
睡吧  晚安
Come on. Good night.
父亲
Father.
准备好了吗
Are you ready?
你若愿意  我们可以多留几日
We could stay longer, if you want.
不
No.
我们回去吧
Let's go home.
这么多书
So many books.
而且种类繁多  包罗万象
And they're all different.
这是人类经验的结晶
All human experience is here.
为什么要藏起来
Why did he hide them?
因为他知道它们的价值
Because he knew their value.
因为他知道我们有朝一日会来取走它们
Because he thought we'd come back for them.
你怎么找到那里的
How did you know where to look?
我们的目的达到了
Well, we got what we came for.
-可以走了吗  -是的
- Shall we go?  - Yes.
我们回去吧
Let's go home.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
今晚很冷
It's colder tonight.
我现在是孤儿了
I'm an orphan now.
能抱抱我吗
Will you hold me?
没别的意思
Nothing else.
只是不想感到孤单
I just don't want to feel alone.
那些不是众神的眼睛
They're not the eyes of the gods;
是逝者的双眸
they're the eyes of those who've passed...
在监护着我们
...watching over us.
我喜欢这说法
I like that.
里昂提斯  跑那么快干嘛
Leontes! What's the hurry?
-怎么了  -一头鹿从我的马前跑了过去
- What happened? - A deer ran in front of my horse.
马儿受惊了  把我扔了下来
It frightened the life out of it... it threw me.
国王的护卫  被一头鹿所伤
The King's champion, wounded by a deer.
你肩膀脱臼了
Your shoulder's come out of the socket.
-我来  -我没事  别碰我
- I'll do it. - I'm fine. Don't touch me.
想点别的  分散注意力
Better think of something else.
试着佯装享受这感觉  明白吗
Just try and pretend like you're not going to enjoy this, all right?
别碰我
Leave it!
里昂提斯
Leontes!
看
Look.
快动手
Now!
好了
There we go.
你能控制它了
So you can control it.
我就说吧  你是个天使
See? You are an angel.
我考虑了所有证词
I've considered all that's been said.
有人曾遭遇了巨大的痛苦
There has been enormous suffering.
我不该有所袒护
There shall be no favours.
判罚必须公正
The punishment must be both fitting
并且适当
and appropriate!
摩根  求求你
Morgan, please!
闭嘴
Quiet.
你必须受点皮肉之苦
You need to accept this.
烧死她
Burn her!
烧死她  好样的  复仇天神
Burn her! Yes! Vengeance!
这就是你要求的惩戒
That is your retribution.
这不够  她必须被处决
It is not enough. She must be executed.
-我已做出了判决  -我女儿丢了性命
- I've given my decision. - My daughter died!
-那是无心之失  -那祭典呢
- That was a mistake! - What about the rituals?
其他被害的女孩呢
The other girls who died?
没有其他女孩被害
No girls died.
她说过有其他女孩被选过
She said they were chosen!
你可不知道被选是什么意思
You have no idea what it means to be chosen.
不得挑衅我的权威
I will not be challenged!
你想让她感受你的痛苦
You want her to feel your pain?
她现在每天都将感同身受
She will now. Every day.
你想用她的命偿还你女儿的命
You want her life for your daughter's?
我不接受
I don't accept that.
她已受到了惩罚  你也得到了你的复仇
She has her punishment. You have your retribution.
现在走吧  否则我就要叫守卫了
Now go, or face my guards.
还有人质疑我的决定吗
Does anyone else wish to dispute my decision?
真美
It is beautiful.
我们会让它更将辉煌
We'll make it more than that...
它将成为后世引以为豪的圣地  我保证
Make it a place to be proud of, I promise.
我相信你
I believe you.
谢谢
Thank you.
很好  这正是我们需要的
Well done. It's exactly what we need.
一个可以思考的地方
A place to think.
举国上下都将如此
The whole nation will be that.
那里怎么样
What was it like?
很美
It was beautiful.
谢谢您沿途如此照顾我的妻子
Thank you for taking such great care of my wife on the journey.
我很庆幸是您一路护送她
If it had to be anyone, I'm grateful it was you.
荣幸之至  很遗憾此行的目的有些伤感
It was my honour. I'm sorry it wasn't for a happier occurrence.
好了  还有很多事要做呢
Right, well, we've still got a lot of work to do.
高文  布拉提斯
Gawain, Brastias,
带30个人去东边的山谷
take 30 men out to the valley in the east.
插上我们的徽旗
Plant banners every mile.
在树林里停下时
When you stop in the woods,
要让人们知道你们在做什么
let everyone know what you're doing.
让他们相互转告  他们将受到保护
Tell them to spread the they are protected.
我们才刚回来啊
We've only just got back.
国王有令  布拉提斯
The King gave an order, Brastias.
快去准备徽旗
Gather up the banners.
我们去东边
We're moving east.
之前是不是有人说要重建屋顶来着
Did I hear of plans to rebuild the roof?
不  我改主意了
No, I've changed my mind.
屋顶将永不封闭
That roof must never be sealed.
永不加盖  如果我们抬头便能仰望天空
Never built over. If we look up and see the sky,
就不会忘记我们所效忠的人们
we'll never forget who we're serving.
就永远不会跟外界隔绝
Never be disconnected from the world outside.
我喜欢这说法
I like that.